We welcome you guys back to Ticket
Master Studios. And it's that time of
year again. And I don't mean March
Madness. It's free agency frenzy in the
NFL. And over the last week, the Falcons
have signed 13 new players to the
roster. At the time that we're recording
this, it's 13. So things can change the
next couple of days, but as of this
moment, 13 players have been signed. I'm
with Dave Archer. I'm Taylor Vizmore.
We're going to go through all 13 of
those players. And I thought, who better
to start with than two guys that are
returning to the Falcons? That is Austin
Hooper, the tight end, and Alamade
Zakias, the wide receiver. Let's
actually start with the tight end and
Austin Hooper. He came in, he was here
as a rookie, spent his rookie contract
here, going to be joining this tight end
room with Kyle Pittz and Charlie Warner,
two guys that play very different roles
at the tight end position. How is Austin
Hooper going to be a good addition to
this tight end room?
>> Taylor, it's crazy. 155 games this guy's
played in the National Football League.
We remember him as a baby back in 2016,
catching a touchdown in the Super Bowl.
But what he does is he brings the
versatility to the position, his ability
to catch the football. He's done an
outstanding job. 430 receptions in his
career. Now, he's bounced around a
little bit since he left Atlanta. I've
been in Cleveland, Tennessee, Las Vegas,
and of course, New England recently.
Been to two Super Bowls. That's don't
don't discount that. His ability to play
in the postseason, understanding what
that's like, but his ability to block on
the edge. Remember, he blocked for two
pretty good backs when he was here in
Devonte Freeman and Kevin Coleman. So,
he has the ability to block on the edge,
but he's an outstanding pass receiver.
Just ask Matt Ryan.
>> Yeah. And as you're seeing on these
highlights, he spent some time with the
Browns under Stfansky. And Stfansky even
said when he was with the Browns, quote,
"Any success we have had on offense,
number 81 is involved. He's been a real
threat in the past. He's been a great
addition in the run game as well. So,
he's going to be a great addition to
this tight end room. Let's go ahead and
switch to Zakias. Another guy who was
with the Falcons not so long ago,
Alamade. I think a lot of people know
who he is, but for the guys for the fans
that might not know a ton about him,
what is he bringing to the wide
receiver?
>> Well, first of all, Amed Zakius is the
all-time leading pass catcher in
Virginia history. 250 receptions as a
Virginia Cavaliier, number two in yards,
number four in touchdowns. That's what
he did at the college level. At this
level, he's been that third receiver,
sometimes that number two receiver, and
he can play across the board. You'll
mainly see him in the slot area. His
ability to catch the ball, his ability
to manipulate coverage. He does an
outstanding job of getting into the end
zone. Aid Zakius is a guy that that he
scored six touchdowns as a Falcon. So,
he's he's had some success there. And
what better scenario could you talk
about with Zakius. His first career
reception was a 93yd touchdown from the
guy that's the president of football,
Matt Ryan. His first catch as an NFL
player. Amid Zakius is going to play all
the way across the board. He's got run
and miss, catch short areas, make people
miss. He's got a lot of ability.
>> It was Zakius's longest touchdown and it
was also Matt Ryan's longest touchdown
as well. Let's kind of stay on the wide
receiver track though. Jan Dodson from
the Eagles. He is joining this wide
receiver room as well. I know that you
mentioned Zakias more of a third
receiver kind of guy. Jan Dodson used to
was a first round pick, 16th overall.
He's joining a room with Drake London as
well. Looking at the three of these
guys, how will they be able to make a
wide receiver unit?
>> Oh, I think that it's going to be
outstanding. This to me, Jan Dodson is
the guy that's been dying for the
opportunity. Okay, number one draft
pick, as Taylor talked about when he
went to Washington, had a chance and
started to kind of blossom as a
Washington commander, then was traded to
Philadelphia and was kind of mired on
the depth chart. Right, Taylor? The next
thing you know, this guy gets an
opportunity to come here. You hear his
interviews. Go to Atlanta Falcons.com,
listen to the interviews with Jan
Dodson, his press conference. He's dying
for the opportunity to get on the field.
This is one of those guys that I think
is a diamond in the rough. Over 2,000
yards receiving as a Nitney Lion his
last two years. He's been waiting for
the opportunity to be that guy that's
going to be targeted as much as he's
going to be targeted here. But you
combine these three guys with Drake
London and some of the other pieces that
are going to come back to training camp.
Man, all of a sudden, you talk about Ian
Cunningham started raise the floor of
what you've got. They just raised the
floor in the wide receiver room.
>> Well, it's so interesting that you say
that he wants it. He wants to go out and
get it. A lot of these guys I've spoken
to this week, not just the free agents,
but the guys on this roster on this on
the pass catching side of the ball, they
are hungry. They want the ball. So,
adding him to a Drake London who always
wants the ball, always wants an
opportunity. It's going to be fun to
watch them come training camp. So, three
pass catchers have been signed by the
Falcons as of right now. But let's talk
about the biggest name for the Falcons
so far in this free agency frenzy
situation to a tongue has been signed by
the Atlanta Falcons. He spent six years
down in Miami as the face of the
Dolphins. What are you getting in a
quarterback in to a tongue?
>> Well, number one, you're getting
experience. Obviously, the guy's played
a ton of football, 78 games in his
career as a Miami Dolphin. But what
you're also getting is you're getting a
winner. Go look at his numbers. 44 wins,
only 32 losses. He wins football games.
Guided the Miami Dolphins two years ago
or three years ago to an 11 and5 record.
He has done an outstanding job of taking
care of the football. 78 career games,
just 59 interceptions. Now, he had a
number of interceptions last year. It
ultimately maybe led to him losing his
job down there, 15 interceptions, but
for the most part and for most of his
career, Tua has done an outstanding job
of taking care of the football. He's a
guy that's an outstanding reader of the
football and outstanding reader of the
game. But a three consecutive years, 100
plus rating as a passer. That's
outstanding as well. So I think people
get caught up in what happened maybe
down there last year in Miami. Go look
at this guy's career. This guy's a
winner and he can make all the throws on
the field. Outstanding touch passer.
>> Couple things to know about Tongabaloa.
In his six years, he has 68% completion
rate, 120 touchdowns, and like you
mentioned before, 59 interceptions. Now,
here is the thing. Because Tonga Valoa
has been a big name and it's been a big
conversation for the Falcons on the
quarterback room and there's only one
position on the field at the time when
it is a quarterback. What's going to
happen with Michael Penn? What's going
to happen with Tua Tong Boa? Ian
Cunningham, the general manager made
himself clear when they were signing Tua
Tong Boa. He said, "We're not in the
business of handling or of handing out
positions for Tua. He knows he's coming
in to compete and so does Michael. There
are no starters right now." kind of
thinking about what Ian is saying in
terms of the competition piece, how
interesting is it going to be to watch
Tuangabiloa and Michael Penn compete for
a starting finish?
>> It's going to be a lot of fun. I think
you're going to end up with a guy that's
really going to be uh kind of christened
in fire, if you will. You love the fact
that Penn has gotten a chance to play
over the last couple of seasons, a
little bit his rookie year, quite a bit
last year before his injury. And then
Tula, we just talked about his
experience and how much he's a winner. I
think they're going to challenge one
another. I think there'll be some
synergy in the room. I don't think
there's going to be that infighting that
you potentially get from time to time. I
think these two guys are going to blend
together and you're going to have the
best guy on the field potentially for
the team.
>> Exactly. All right. So, Ian Cunningham,
like he said, there is going to be a a
competition, but that's not just at the
quarterback position. That's at every
single position. But something else that
Ian Cunningham really believes in is
building through the trenches and he's
already gotten off to a start um in the
trenches on both sides of the ball.
First of all, they they have signed Cory
Lean, the seven-year offensive lineman
out of Tennessee Titans. And then on the
defensive side of the ball, this is
where things get really interesting
because there are four guys that have
been added to the trenches for this
defensive line. Let's kind of talk about
Chris Williams and Deshawn Hand. Two
guys that have a lot of experience. One
coming from the Bears and Williams and
the other coming from the Chargers in
hand. David Onada did leave the Falcons
leaving an interior position open for
these two guys to compete for or rotate
into. What will they bring into an
interior defensive line room? Yeah, I
think Taylor, you think of a defensive
line room as not necessarily, yeah,
there's a guy that's going to line up
the opening snap and maybe play the
first five or six snaps, but then you
get, as you mentioned, that rotation.
So, it's more about four, five, maybe
even six guys are going to rotate at the
defensive tackle position, maybe in
rundowns, even slide out and play a five
technique or a seven technique on the
edge of a defense because he's got a
little bit more size against the run
game. Versatility, outstanding
versatility. Deshawn uh Deshan Han 77
games in his career now. He's played
with three different three different
organizations, but it's a guy that
understands what it takes to play at the
defensive tackle position. And again,
you're not asking him to come in and
play 70 snaps a game. He's going to play
his 40 snaps or so a game and they're
going to rotate other guys in. I know
you want to talk about Chris as well,
Chris Williams.
>> Well, listen, I Chris Williams also
another guy coming in from the Bears.
one of the guys Ian new get to get him
to the Bears and then again bringing him
in in free agency. What will Chris
Williams bring to interior defensive
line? A lot of experience the last two
years. He's played 31 games for the
Chicago Bears over the last two seasons.
And that's where the familiarity with
the in Cuttingham and Chris Williams. He
knows the effort that this guy gives.
Throw the tape on. Go to YouTube,
wherever you want to go. Go to go to
Atlanta Falcons.com. Put his headlines
his highlights on. He's an effort guy
and he fits the defense perfectly. What
Jeff talks about is getting up the
field, creating problems in the blocking
schemes by aggressive uh attacks in the
front. That's what this guy is. That's
what he does. He gets up the field. You
will even see him make plays, run guys
down from high. He's about 300 lb, but
he's got outstanding quickness and
agility in the interior. He'll be part
of that rotational piece that you can
line hang into. The thing you go back to
is what Ian Cuttingham talked about.
we've raised the floor. Okay. So, when a
guy goes out and you plug another guy
in, what he's talking about is there's
no drop off when another player comes
in. Chris Williams is going to aid in
that.
>> You mentioned it earlier about this
defensive front. And what Jeff Olrich as
a defensive coordinator likes to do,
it's to have rotation, consistent
rotation all game long, all practice
long, all training camp long. They want
these guys to get short reps, come off,
rest your legs, and then go back in and
be able to play all four quarters at a
very high level. So, of course, they
bring in a lot more guys to, like you
said, elevate the floor. Cameron Thomas
is joining the Falcons coming off from
being with the Browns for four years.
This is the first one that they signed,
the first player that they signed in
free agency. He just finished working
with Kevin Stfansky. What does that say
to you? That's Kevin Stfansky in his
first free agency as a Falcons head
coach said, "This is the guy I want. I
want him signed now. I want him on my
team
>> because when you get that kind of an
endorsement from a coach, and it's a
great point, Taylor, in that you know
the kind of guy you're bringing into
your building, right? There's got to be
a synergy. There's got to be a feeling
in the building of going to work. I
mean, Brick talks about it all the time.
Heart, mind, fist. Heart meaning you you
bring you bring that work ethic. You're
going to work hard. You're going to work
every moment of every day. You're in
every meeting. uh mind you, you know
what you're supposed to do and then
fist, you bring the physicality. This
guy might typify that. That's why
Stfansky went and got him because he
knows he's going to get those three
principles when they bring Cam Thomas
in. So, I think that that's the part
that you hang your hat on. Then, oh, by
the way, he can play the game and he can
play it in the interior piece. He's 270
lbs. He could slide him inside. He can
also play in those scenarios where you
play him on the edge against the run. I
think there's a lot of versatility to
Cam Thomas and the reason he's here is
because of what he attitude he brings to
the building.
>> You bring up Heartmind Fist and someone
that's known for the fist for the
physicality of how they play is Samson
Abukcom who comes from um the Colts. He
has had a great season um a great career
so far. Of course had the Achilles
injury two years ago and has been in
recovery ever since. Had played last
season but still finding that recovery.
What are you getting in a defensive end
in Abukam? Again, you're going to get a
rotational guy on the edge, a guy that's
got tremendous experience. Abacama has
been around for a while now, 127 games,
only 31 years of old of age. He'll turn
31 May 9. So, I don't want to take away
his last couple of months of being 30,
but he turns 31. So, a lot of
experience. We actually played against
Ebacom again when he was the 49ers and
uh he created some problems for us. This
is a guy that understands how to play
the edge. He's about 245 250 lbs and
he'll be a part of that rotation with
the guys on the outside that can be as
you mentioned throwing numbers at him
but the numbers that you're throwing at
him are higher level numbers maybe than
what we had before from a ability
standpoint and an experience standpoint.
Ebam brings that to the table.
>> Let me ask you this before we transition
to the linebacker room really fast. He
used to be a linebacker when he was at
the Rams. He was a linebacker. Then they
transitioned him to a defensive end.
Knowing what you that that he has all
that experience, how does that help him
in terms of rushing the passer and
getting after the quarterback?
>> Yeah. The versatility that Taylor talks
about, his ability to line up on the
edge where he puts his hand in the dirt
or whether he stands up, the ability to
drop off in coverage because remember,
you're not going to try to you're going
to you want to mix up the quarterback.
You want to show different looks. So, he
may have to get off in coverage. He has
the ability to do that as Taylor just
talked about because he played some some
linebacker on that in that outside
linebacker position. but understanding
how to set the edge in the run game, but
also being able to rush the passers. You
talked about this team set a record in
sacks this last year. They do not want
to take a step back. Ed Cam's going to
help them stay right where they wanted
to be.
>> All right, let's talk about the
linebackers cuz I know everyone calls
the Philadelphia Eagles, the Philly
Dogs, but what about Atlanta? I think
Atlanta's kind of becoming the Atlanta
Dogs a little bit cuz there's two
Georgia Bulldogs that are joining the
linebacker room. And that's a third
linebacker from the University of
Georgia joining this room. Let's talk
about Aziz Ojelari really quickly.
Coming in 22 sacks, 22 tackles for loss,
38 quarterback hits and four force
fumbles. What are you getting in a
former um Giant and Eagle and Aizo
Gelari?
>> Ojelari was a guy that came out in the
draft if you remember and he ended up
going number two or was a was a draft
pick for the Giants where he was a
featured edge player and he was a guy
that's going to come off and get after
the quarterback. 35 sacks in his career
now or so I'm sorry 22 sacks in his
career but he's a guy that's that has uh
a little bit what do you talk about with
the Jan Datson thing hasn't quite
reached the or been maybe given been
given the opportunity to get to the
level he potentially could get to again
a rotational guy I keep using the the
term that that Ian Cunningham used in
that they've raised the floor the
players are going to plug in when
someone comes out the next guy that
comes in Ojelari is going to be one of
those guys and and It doesn't it doesn't
hurt to come home and play where you
played your high school football. He
played at Marietta High School. So, he's
he's gets to come home. We know Taylor
just mentioned he played with the
Georgia Bulldogs. But, it's kind of cool
to be able to come home. You know, ask
AJ Terrell and some of the guys that
have had a chance to do that.
>> Yeah. I actually got to sit down and
talk to him and I said, "You and Charlie
are the only two players in this locker
room that got to play high school here,
got to play college here, and got to
play in the NFL here. What does this
mean to and he said, "I'm so excited to
get like get to work, be with this team,
and be part of the Atlanta Falcons." So,
it's you could tell when he got in this
room, he is so excited to be an Atlanta
Falcon. Let's talk about another UG
Grouden Channing Tindle, linebacker, of
course, but he's really known more for
his special teams play. What are you
getting in Tindle as a special teams
player?
>> Well, you're getting a four-phase
player. That means he's going to play on
both the coverage units and both the
kick units. So kickoff coverage, kick uh
punt coverage, and then flip it over,
return for both those disciplines as
well. He ran 44 at the combine. So he's
got tremendous athleticism, but he's a
guy that's a seek and destroy type
player. Anybody that remembers him at
the University of Georgia, he had 12
sacks. He has some versatility to him,
and I think that's the part that they
liked a lot. Obviously, they love Coach
Aman, the the uh special teams coach
that coached him in Miami, knows very
much what this guy brings to the table.
But I think they also liked I think he
walked in the room and and convinced
maybe Brick. He said, "Hey, here's a guy
that we could potentially blitz or do
some things with from an athletic
standpoint in a linebacker position that
maybe raises again the floor of the
linebacker room, potentially have
Channon Tindel." Tinddale, I know he's
excited to come back. He's a South
Carolina guy, but he played at Georgia.
Um, so he's excited to be back in the
room as well.
>> And let me tell you, those two
linebackers are so excited to work with
Jaylen Walker again, a former Buckus
award winner. I mean, it's going to be
fun watching the three of those guys
work together cuz they not all three of
them did not work together at the
University of Georgia. So, it's going to
be fun to watch them during training
camp and throughout the season. Let's
kind of transition though, speaking of
special teams, to two special teams
players that came through for the
Falcons pretty early in this free agency
process. That is punter Jake Bailey and
kicker Nick Folk. Let's talk about Jake
Bailey first because something that I
thought was so interesting when Stfansky
first got here is he said I want this
special teams unit to be very detailed
and Aman said the same exact thing that
he wants him to be detailed in
everything that they do and that he
loves coverages. He is like he said I'm
a big nerd when it comes to the
coverage. I want great kick coverage. I
want great p um punt coverage. What is
Jake Bailey giving you in those two
things that Stansky and Achan are
looking for? Well, again, high a high
highend average, first of all.
Obviously, you want to know the guy can
get it out of there and kick it out of
there. And um he averaged just under 47
yards a kick for his career, but over
the last two seasons, he's averaged 47
plus per kick. And the number you'd like
to look at, too, and some of this is
going to have to do with the Channing
Tisdale of the world that are going to
cover, but his net is right at 42 yards.
And that's really on the high end. If
you're netting after a punt 42 yards,
you're truly flipping the field. And
that's what Jake Bailey can do. He's a
pro bowler, all throw back in 20, but uh
he the last two years I think he's had
two of his best years of his career. And
we're getting him off of that after
averaging over 47 yards a kick.
>> Bailey when he first got to the league
was with the Patriots and he won the
punter job. It was a big competition for
the Patriots at the time. He won the job
and he's actually even worked with the
kicker that the Falcons just signed in
Nick Fulk. The two are so excited to be
back together working with each other
again. And when you talk about someone
in the special teams room that is
consistent, doesn't get much more
consistent than this guy right here. He
is one of um the more seasoned players
in the NFL. And he has a since 2023, he
is the most consistent kicker in the
league. What are you getting from Nick
Folk in terms of consistency?
>> I'm going to accentuate what Taylor just
said. He's had 71 field goal attempts
for the last three seasons. He's missed
three times.
>> He's 68 of 71. And to even push that
further, Taylor, he's 18 of 20 from 50
plus over the last three years. You
think, wait a minute, he's 41 years old.
Last year, he had his career-long 58
yard field goal sail through for the
Jets last year. There's nobody that's
been more consistent than this guy over
the last three seasons. And in his
career, he's an 85% kicker. The guy has
been phenomenal. Uh very, very
consistent. He can kick off. He can do
all the things and I think Jake can do
that as well. These two guys will
probably look at maybe both sharing the
kickoff duties which we've done in
recent years as well. But coach Aerman
excited to have Nick Fer.
>> Let me ask you this because in the last
couple of years I would say maybe even
like the last handful of years for the
Falcons, a lot of the games that they
have either won or lost have come down
to a score or less. Why is having a
consistent kicker that can go out there
any given Sunday, any given prime time
game and put it through the uprights so
important for this organization?
>> Yeah, the the the experience that Taylor
is talking about and think about try to
put yourself in a position. Okay, you
stand on the sidelines maybe the whole
game and and you've gotten out for a
couple extra points and maybe you kicked
the field goal in the second quarter,
but here we are in the final seconds of
the game and you're going to get shoved
out there. Do you have that mentality to
be able to do that? guy has been there,
done that repeatedly over and over.
That's why he's still around. He's still
kicking at 41 years of age. And we just
talked about he's had the three best
years of his career over the last three
seasons. Oh, by the way, his longest
field goal of his career happened last
season. So, I I think that it kind of
goes without even saying you really like
the experience and you love the fact
that he's been there and done that.
>> Yeah, he is one of the guys that's on
the longer term contracts, I guess, for
this overall free agency group. P is on
a two-year deal. Jake Bailey is on a
three-year deal. For the most part,
everyone else is on a one-year deal. Let
me ask you about that really quickly as
we wrap up. Now, why is it important for
Ian Cunningham in this front office to
be signing guys on these short-term
contracts?
>> Well, first of all, you get an
opportunity. A guy comes in and let's
put yourself in a position of a player
that's coming in on a one-year contract.
It's a proven opportunity. Yeah, it's a
proven opportunity for the team that you
signed for, the Atlanta Falcons. But
there's 31 other teams out there that
are watching your team. If you want to
stay in this league in the NFL a lot of
times, and you've heard it said before,
the NFL says it stands for not for long.
That means not for long if you're not
getting your job done. But for for
Cuttingham, it's an opportunity for them
to begin to clear cap space. We got we
got some issues along those lines that
they're trying to satisfy, but also
gives an opportunity for these guys to
come in and say, "Hey, I want to be at
the Lana Falcon for a longer period of
time." Well, okay, let let's go see.
Let's go earn it. Let's go find out. And
then it also sets the table for what
they can do vision-wise as far as
looking at other free agents that are
going to come available down the road.
Remember Ian said it a couple of times,
Taylor. He's told you and I
>> we're this is just the beginning of free
agency. Free agency is a long-term
scenario. Free agency is going to run
probably all the way into into the into
the season. He's constantly working on
trying to enhance this roster. I'll tell
you what, Taylor, I think you and I both
agree he's done a pretty good job of
enhancing it so far.
>> It he has. like you've mentioned a
couple times, he's elevated the floor.
It's what he said what he wanted to do
in free agency is elevate the floor of
this roster and as we know he loves
draft picks and the NFL draft is just a
little bit over a month away. So, as
free agency continues, we're going to
start preparing for the NFL draft. We
will see you um in at the end of April
for the NFL draft. Thanks, guys.